<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>openstack on Jason's Braindump</title><link>https://jason.haikebang.com/tags/openstack/</link><description>Recent content in openstack on Jason's Braindump</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 17:10:41 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jason.haikebang.com/tags/openstack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to create OpenStack image of running instance?</title><link>https://jason.haikebang.com/posts/20220627170712-how_to_create_openstack_image_of_running_instance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 17:10:41 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jason.haikebang.com/posts/20220627170712-how_to_create_openstack_image_of_running_instance/</guid><description> Stop the instance from either the UI or CLI. $ openstack server stop [instance UUID] Take a snapshot of the running instance. $ openstack server image create --name [snapshot name] [instance UUID] List the images and identify the UUID of the snapshot using the name given during creation. $ openstack image list</description></item><item><title>How to make image?</title><link>https://jason.haikebang.com/posts/how-to-make-image/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 23:08:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jason.haikebang.com/posts/how-to-make-image/</guid><description>For a Linux-based image to have full functionality in an OpenStack Compute cloud, there are a few requirements. For some of these, you can fulfill the requirements by installing the cloud-init package. Read this section before you create your own image to be sure that the image supports the OpenStack features that you plan to use.
Disk partitions and resize root partition on boot (cloud-init)
When you create a Linux image, you must decide how to partition the disks.</description></item><item><title>OpenStack</title><link>https://jason.haikebang.com/posts/openstack/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 16:58:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jason.haikebang.com/posts/openstack/</guid><description>FAQ How to make image? How to create OpenStack image of running instance? TODO What is the Cloud Image? Boot an instance from an ISO image https://docs.openstack.org/ocata/user-guide/cli-nova-launch-instance-using-ISO-image.html
Troubleshooting The main troubleshooting method about OpenStack is checking through the logs.
Network What is physical network in OpenStack? The OpenStack Networking services can either run together on the same physical server, or on separate dedicated servers, which are named according to their roles:</description></item></channel></rss>